This is the last session of the day in here.
You guys have done an incredible job making it this far.
Yay, yay! All of us.
Yeah!
Wow! Amazing. Cool.
This is Robert Overweg.
He is going to be talking to us about something.
I am really excited about this one brain concept.
I was chatting his ear off just a second ago, because at Tessl,
we've been focused on the kind of linear issue to merged
PR orchestration pipeline.
But the more we do that, the more we realize that actually pre
is really what matters.
That decision making and that scoping is actually the hardest part
and kind of makes the rest look trivial.
So I'm really excited for this.
Let's give him a round of applause.
Yes. Hello everyone
and thanks for having me and thanks for staying around.
And I'm also aware
that I'm the laws piece standing between you and a party and beer.
So I'll try to keep it short, but also keep it interactive.
So my name is Robert and today we're going to talk about one
brain, how you can create one brain for the organization.
I do have to say we aren't like this a large enterprise.
We're still like a startup.
So for us, maybe it's easier, but it's also easier for us to experiment
and try out new things.
And I want to share some of our learnings and also
some of our failures in a way,
because for us, it originated from these type
of frustrations, often like, hey, where's this file?
Where's this presentation?
You know, you're always looking for these kind of things, chasing people.
It's really irritating, at least for me.
Or when I am working in the morning like 5:00 or late in the evening.
And I actually want to get a prototype out really quickly, then
it would be useful for me to know if that prototype
is actually for 500
SKUs, so unique units, or if it's for 5000.
And when that's not properly
communicated to me, know it's difficult for me to set everything up.
But if I am connected to the,
sort of all of the all of the knowledge of the organization
that was also part of, like meetings and conversations,
then I'm just really easily able to sort of channel that and,
bring that forward and use it in my work.
Now, I would like to press the next slide ideally.
Let's see, I can also try a different port.
Who knows.
Let's see.
Hey. Or a very small subject on hey,
how can we actually improve our agentic pipeline?
Really really large I understand, but these are the type of questions
that also surface in organizations.
Now, I do have to say that we work mainly in in fashion for these type of brands.
So big brands and we do a lot of high volume image visual work for those guys.
But I also have to say we're a small team.
So that combined doing large volume work
and small team and then creating these type of work.
So what you see here is a lady that we created is a digital person.
She is currently being hired
to orient it to Tommy Hilfiger, Calvin Klein and GE star.
And we also create this type of
imagery video based on created through AI.
And we do that at scale.
So we do these type of things, but we don't just do that one thing.
We have got five, six more modules.
So we need to produce a ton of content, a ton of stuff.
So we really can't be occupied with trying to find folders,
trying to find stuff.
So we really have to work in AI native way just to be able to cope
with the gigantic output.
So that's basically the sort of the setting that we're in.
And I think that's really helpful also for, for innovation
because we kind of have to now that's what I said at the top.
So we're trying to continuously learn about everything.
And then we're also continuously trying to surface the right information
at the right time.
We see two types of information.
One is the company knowledge.
So things like new developments, new things are happening in the space in terms
of like codex goal or new type of skills
or research wikis that we create
making meeting knowledge secure, accessible.
And then there's also in the creation pipeline, making sure that
that the evils are stricter, making sure that skills are getting optimized.
So there's two kinds of knowledge that we try to optimize for.
Now we started really simple.
And you can start in such a way as well.
So we just started with OpenClaw on a sandbox environment.
Then GitHub is a repository that has the data,
like all the research and those kind of things.
And then we use I use obsidian
to also have it locally on my system so that I can browse through it.
And I'll show you how that's set up as well.
Obsidian I find it way better than stuff like notion.
Notion always was so slow to load and really clunky it didn't really like it.
So if people are fan,
but I'm just more of a fan of obsidian because it's really fast and snappy.
And then telegram is, yeah, the, the, the, the surface through which I can just
communicate 20 for seven, like a little bit of psychopath because,
you know, you could wake up in the morning and then you can sort of ask your agent
or I walk on the street
and then I'm just talking into my phone like this to find the information
or to share information really, really useful.
Now we are actually at this stage and I'll show a bit later how all of this works.
So, because yeah, it can become
it's not necessarily that complex, but it can become more complex gradually.
But it's good to see that some people take photos.
But it's good to start here, I think, because then from there
you can just, continue building yourself.
But I'll explain these things a bit later.
And also what are specific setup was for each of these components.
Now, what you get in return.
Like I said before, right.
I have sort of all, not all most of our company knowledge on my phone.
And I can just send all the messages, all the messages, or type myself
to surface the information, which is really, really valuable.
So one example here I can talk through natural language.
So I again forgot what we wanted to implement in our CI/CD pipeline.
And but I did
remember that it was from Microsoft and they had like these four steps
or something.
So I just asked my, my agent, what was that thing again
for the CI/CD things.
And then it says, oh, you probably mean
this and this and this and this, which was actually accurate.
And then it also because it understands my context.
It also asked is this for the talk which is also really useful.
So I just continuously have this sparring body.
So what we're doing
is we no longer search for files, but more like for ideas and context
and those kind of things, which is a massive game changer.
Then we have agents as well.
So I have a agent that proactively does search for me,
and I have agent that is able to interpret search that I find myself.
I want to show some examples here as well.
Maybe you guys have this already right.
And this is really also quite basic, but we have a grand job
or I have a cron job that runs on my OpenClaw that that tracks
certain accounts on X, those accounts,
just, on just some specific words so
you can think of agentic engineering or, or any words
that relate to such pipelines that I'm interested in.
I follow some niche accounts as well. Or niche.
I think a guy has maybe like 120 K followers, maybe not that niche,
but I do stay in in touch with everything that is happening.
And it's almost like my newspaper because I don't read the newspaper,
but I read everything.
Evolving around, agents and AI and those kind of things.
And that's being surfaced to me, daily in the morning.
But what
we did figure out what was really useful is that obviously you don't want
to put all of those things in your own vault or repository.
So what we do is
I promote stuff to the vault, which I, which like this is really important.
You need to remember this once.
After a while, I figure out that it's actually really, really important.
Then I create Vickie's out of it.
And those wikis, their service to the wider team because I don't want to,
bother and bore everyone with my research.
You know, it.
It needs to find some grounding in reality.
Okay.
Let's see what.
Happened there.
Yeah.
Do we visual again?
Perfect.
So here is also, a very good example.
So I found this, skill from at least a skill as part of a larger skill
pack from. Adios, Marni. Guy from Google.
This was for, skill breakdown of larger tasks.
And I thought, okay, this could be really interesting, but here
I just asked my agent, like, hey, is this actually interesting for us?
And since it understands which skills we have, our code base
setup, what we want to do, it's able to analyze.
I need to steer it a little bit because I need to say,
hey, don't we have surgery starts breakdown already?
So developer we work with and then it's like, actually I'll have a better look.
And then at the end it's able to say and summarize Adios money skills
and nothing you don't already have your task files actually more detailed.
I'm like, yay!
Also, if you look at the time here, it's
five plus eight here and it's six plus eight at the end.
So in one minute you analyzed that skill, came to a conclusion,
and we can decide that we're not going to put it in the vault.
Now I want to show you a couple of things.
That's why I have this checklist here.
So I don't forget.
So in our vault.
I have a lot of research, as you can see here on the left. And
that's all rather unstructured.
It's almost 1200 files, but it's this setup is able to cope
with all of these things without doing additional, additional stuff.
We started doing additional things like rack and factors
and that kind of stuff, but it's not really needed.
In those files
I add my to dos also related related notes.
Sometimes I create connections myself and like actually this file needs to be
connected to that so that we keep it as sort of like a memory hub together.
And also if you look, if you look here.
So here I ask my chat agent.
So here in general.
How did Opec+ search work again?
Then it was like, hey, can you clarify what you mean?
Are you thinking of x, y, z?
And then I clarify and here it gives me exactly how it works.
So yeah, I can also even keep up to date with the things I,
make up myself.
And then here we have like the, the, the daily
daily update here I also get status updates on security things here.
You can also see that new meetings have been had by other people.
So I'm just getting notified like, hey, this person had a meeting.
That transcript is available for you.
So I've shown you the obsidian research,
the telegram chat, and also the notifications.
Also, if there are any questions.
Yeah, I guess we have to park
those a little bit too, to the end.
And then we have another vault
which has all sorts of client information.
So we work with, like I said earlier, a lot of files
and also a lot of our clients work in a variety of different ways.
So some work with Miro to map out our gears.
Some work with PowerPoints, some work with inodes, some work with Figma.
And it's quite difficult to get people to change and work in different ways.
So we sort of figured out, let's just interpret whatever they give to us
and then put that into our system, and that works really well.
And this entire system is also based on natural language.
So you can just say to it.
Hey, what were the loss files from Calvin Klein that we got delivered from X
and Y person, which is really, also really, really useful
when you run production.
So where is that asset?
That's no longer an issue, which makes me happy because we can
then just focus on building things and we need to build a lot.
I think this is also part of a sort
of larger fundamental philosophical concept.
And this is from Jack Dorsey, founder of Twitter and Block, Inc.
And he said the emergence of AI is challenged,
the premise of hierarchy as a requirement for the first time.
So where we have, you know, in enterprising business, all of these levels
with, middle management,
which we sort of used for communication, but there's also a lot of issues there.
So what if information can be modeled, understood and distributed in real time?
The organization still needs coordination mechanisms centered on people.
What if because the agents are sort of smart enough
to keep interpreting everything?
Not always.
Sometimes they
interpret in in the wrong way, but mostly it's really, really useful.
So we thought, yeah.
Shouldn't we just make as much as possible as humanly?
No pun intended.
Available for for the AI.
So that's every conversation that we have.
Meetings, research also our code base obviously.
And it was also a little bit inspired by what I read,
I think almost, almost ten, 15 years ago by Ray Dalio.
And they had these headphones called what is called again.
Bridgewater.
Yeah.
But they recorded every meeting back then already back then I thought it was.
Yeah, a bit weird, but maybe I was just in a sort of a low
trust environment because right now I feel like, dude,
we should record everything because everything
that is not, like, digitized sort of doesn't exist,
and you're already a disadvantage if you don't do that.
So now we also ordered this thing.
Still waiting for it. It's called Omi.
Omi is open source.
Application open source technology.
Which records, what we say and, well, when you finally send it over,
because I'd be waiting for it for like three weeks.
But when you have, like, coffee outside or somewhere else, you can just put it
on the table, it records it, and you can send it to your own servers.
So there's no, like, subscription stuff, which is really good.
So you can own the data, which I think is really good.
And then granola is a very useful tool for us as well,
which transcribes the meetings, but in a proper way.
And you can also type your own notes at the same time.
And then when it makes the the full transcript, it
prioritize molds it around your notes, which is really useful.
So here we are in the view that I see my co-founders,
all of his meeting nodes, which is pretty useful.
And then it can connect through MCP or API to it.
It's also nice.
And then afterwards when you have like a cloud design
or an open design, if you have those meeting nodes already,
you could practically generate the presentation
that you then need to send to the person that you talk to.
Semi-Automatic.
At least you could get like a first draft, which is also pretty nice.
So these type of questions that we have here,
we can also surface these through the meetings that have me recorded.
So I think if you work more remotely
and more digital, yeah, you could just record everything.
It's really, really beneficial.
So it could be more beneficial if you are further apart, which is kind of funny.
This is honored to do so.
We haven't developed this yet, but as a co-founder
like I am in sort of production, I'm I'm in sales.
I mean like positioning.
You're trying to do everything at the same time, and sometimes you maybe
forget to ask like the right type of sales questions.
So when we have meetings, but like the things
that we need to ask in these sessions, we do know.
So what if our chief of staff just surfaces
these type of questions that we need to ask to the client in that specific call.
So it can also help us think along.
And this is maybe a useful message for you guys.
Like I would not want my knowledge to sit in just cloud or in
or in other people's context windows.
I'd like to, keep it as much as possible on, like, our own,
our own stack and our own server so we can query it and the keeping it
real section because it's very, very messy to, to build these kind of things.
At least it was for me and for us.
So we had a lot of, conflicts in loading issues.
You can update stuff on obsidian as well, and then you can have like all sorts
of merge, merge conflicts with your with
actual GitHub repository, which is not fun.
This is an interesting one.
Knowledge sharing, like in general is could be rather difficult because are you
really going to share all the meetings that you have with everyone?
Because what if you mentioned something that really should not sort of leak out?
So, so we, we have
certain setups basically for that, that, make that less of an issue.
And, and yeah, so we made some boundaries between people, teams and clients
and just, knowledge moves sort of throughout the stack.
Another thing to call out that as you guys already know as well,
right, it the AI can be brilliant and dumb at the same time.
It can sort of lose sight of the most obvious things that you thought.
How do you thought, like I said, is already ten times or it just doesn't
understand like very basic things, but can be brilliant at the same time.
And then I had a lot of issues with just scripts
breaking and jobs not working and that kind of stuff.
So it's a pretty once you got it set up, it works.
But then when you want to start adding new stuff to it, becomes a full time job.
So, to come back to that early complex drawing that it showed
how everything was connected, this is how it, works for us.
So I've got my own private vault with all of those
research documents and that kind of stuff that's connected to GitHub.
I did add G-Brain to it.
It's from Gary Tan, the, CEO, I think of Y Combinator.
And through that I added a big factor.
And, this is also also makes use of ZeroEntropy.
So I've got vector keywords, graph relations between pages, etc.
and well, but I do experience that
I don't really need it for the amount of files that I currently have.
It seems to be that like after a larger amount, it becomes more, more useful.
And then we also have a chief of staff,
which is also on a separate instance,
because I don't want everything to sort of leak over into each other.
And then telegram is the way to, at least for me to communicate.
And like I showed, we have obsidian and I'm looking into Neo4j
to, like add another layer of knowledge,
sort of filtering to it.
And then here's a, there's a,
there's a, there's a deeper dive on,
let's see what kind of, Oh yeah.
Actually how the OpenClaw search works.
So, we have memory search, so semantic search over memory
and topic files, services, preferences decisions and pulse context.
And we have the vault context loads of relevant slice
of the vault by toss type coding toss loads. Ava.
That's our enterprise, stack for self-serve
and then G-Brain if it's like a larger search.
And then we also have direct file reads
and then, Yeah.
So for an example for today.
The talk questions hit the DevCon slides directly.
And I had some stuff on haiku because I want to reduce or spend
because it can be a rather expensive to keep this running,
especially if you run it for multiple multiple people.
Yeah.
So my advice would be to,
start small, let one person suffer through it first.
Don't roll this out to everyone.
And, yeah, why not keep it like, really, really local?
Just on.
You can also just run it on your own laptop to make sure that everything is,
working properly and make sure that you have proper security
hardening on everything that you do, and make sure that you also align
with what you're actually allowed to do with the data.
And I would also set up a chief of staff agents,
because people often say that they don't have any time,
which is true because they are so often in all sorts of meetings and finding stuff.
But if you can give them an agent that that sort of shaves off
20% of all of those jobs, that they find a little bit of a nuisance,
and then they get their time back and then they can actually look more
into these type of, optimization things.
And then that research
agent is just magic, you know, to constantly get that information
in and be able to learn from the world through your curated lens.
And then, yeah, basically see what you want
to promote to the wider group.
And, that's it from sort of
how we build our own internal brain and our.
Yeah, almost like a hive mind.
And if there are any questions, please feel free to ask.
Thank you so much, Robert.
That was so interesting.
I honestly think this kind of thing is going to be like table
stakes for everyone in tech in like a year's time.
Does anyone have any questions for Robert?
What concerns do
you have about like growing that customer files amount?
Like how do you see that scaling?
Do you see G-Brain being able to handle that?
Or do you think that you're going to have to go near 4G,
or do you think there's even something after that?
I run out of breath. That's a that's a good question.
So the, the brain
that works with the company files, that is still fully local
on one person's laptop
because we're still figuring out how we want to expose that.
So unfortunately, I don't have an answer yet to your question.
Like locally, it's able to surface all the things that it needs,
but we still need to look into, stuff like permissions
and making sure that all the data keeps being segregated in like, its own buckets.
Yeah, especially with all the different data types as well.
There's going to be a real struggle.
Correct. Interesting. Thank you.
Anyone else?
How much of a time cost was this to get everything
set up on autonomously running and to maintain?
Yeah.
The first thing that popped in my mind was an insane amount.
But also it's a little bit of like a hobby.
It's it's you become a bit obsessed.
And so I have in my DNA that I just
continuously want to learn and read new things.
So it's it's just part of my nature.
So it doesn't really feel like work, but, Yeah.
Difficult to say, man.
Maybe like, a month of work to get these things set up.
But the good news is once but even open clause setting that up with the right
like containers dockers with the right permissions can be an issue.
But once you've got it set up, it's also a script.
And then it can be 30 minutes or 30s.
30s. You heard him.
Yeah.
Once you got it set up right, once someone suffered through it all,
but then they, they update conflicts and then they come with a new version.
And, I had that the other day that, like, half of my things broke.
It's not ideal.
Hi. How are.
The team members interacting with it?
I mean, it's just a rich
source of information for your team, but as you said, it's very difficult.
But permissions and everything and expensive.
And how are how are the team members interacting with this.
So I had another kind of slightly different question though, is also just
I've done some work in the luxury industry as well, but actually understanding how
qualitative information is like,
you just allow the AI to kind of structure
itself and understand semantically what the information you're working with.
Or are you thinking like, you know, in a structured way
about how to characterize this kind of information as well?
Sure. Yeah.
Let me first try to answer the the first bit, how people interact with it.
So like 80% of the stuff that you see here, we keep with,
just with the leadership team at first and then we promote
wikis with all sorts of knowledge to the, the wider group.
And that's way, way
less that's maybe like 10 to 15 things, but they are rather packed.
So that could be how to work
better with a generic how to reduce bugs, how to do those kind of things.
And to answer your question, in regards to the client data we have now over,
I guess, half a million data points on what the art directors like.
So there's a lot of subjective and yeah, we just yeah, interpret that.
We do have a system in place that also feeds that back into our production.
Yeah.
Why did you pick Open Claw as your orchestrator
and how have you found it suitable or unsuitable for this exercise.
Yeah.
So I found it really suitable because I don't need to have any other,
like actually I don't need any other stuff like G-Brain to
index the data when it's almost like 1500 different, rather large markdown files.
So it worked really well.
But I didn't do a very large
industry wide scan of everything that was available.
I think I started using this
well rather quickly after it sort of got got released.
And yeah, just really like it.
I like it, it's proactive as well.
And I guess, like you're now able to build more agents on top of this
within, within the same orchestrator as many as you need
on top of this knowledge base. Correct. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
And then so the, the,
the, the, the place that the, the Vikings get promoted to
that is on like a separate, separate database that then other agents
can also talk to because I don't want that on my OpenClaw setup.
I do want to keep those things.
Separated.
Thank you for the talk.
I was going to ask actually, a similar question.
Have you thought of using Hermes?
Because that's what I'm.
That's what I decided to use.
And also, have you ever tried any coding along with the agent?
You know, trying to streamline coding processes, but.
Or is it just about this?
No, definitely.
So first on Hermes.
So it came out after Open Claw.
So I did wonder if I should set up a different,
like an additional agent to troubleshoot all the things that consistently break.
So I thought maybe use Hermes and then find out how that works,
but it just didn't
have the sort of the mental bandwidth and the time to to look into that.
But since this.
Yes, sort of works, I don't really have a reason to, to look into that.
What was your other question? Sorry.
I also try to streamline coding.
Coding along with agent.
Yeah, yeah.
So, we're working on a full dark factory pipeline, and then,
Open Claw is the orchestrator there, which triggers the right
skills, let's other adversarial agents do reviews and those kind of things,
but it also just connects to, to Codex, and that does the bulk of the work.
But we do own sort of the orchestration and all of the,
yeah, basically agent harnessing kind of stuff around it.
But that's also a constant I don't want to say battle,
but it's a constant, let's say experiment.
Yeah.
Okay.
Would you guys mind staying for 20s after we give Robert a big round of applause?
Thank you very much.
Hopefully Robert will be at the party, which starts